Fifty million people watched but no one saw a thing.
Quiz Show is a history, drama film directed by Robert Redford.
Herbert Stempel's transformation into an unexpected television personality unfolds as he secures victory on the cherished American game show, 'Twenty-One.' However, when the
show introduces the highly skilled contestant Charles Van Doren to replace Stempel, it compels Stempel to let out his frustrations and call out the show as rigged.
Lawyer Richard Goodwin steps in and attempts to uncover the
orchestrated deception behind the scenes.
Herb Stempel, played by John Turturro.
Dick Goodwin, played by Rob Morrow.
Charles Van Doren, played by Ralph Fiennes.
Mark Van Doren, played by Paul Scofield.
Dan Enright, played by David Paymer.
Albert Freedman, played by Hank Azaria.
Quiz Show is a 1994 American historical mystery-drama film
directed and produced by Robert Redford.
Dramatizing the Twenty-One quiz show scandals of the 1950s, the
screenplay by Paul Attanasio adapts the memoirs of Richard N.
Goodwin, a U.S.
Congressional lawyer who investigated the
accusations of game-fixing by show producers.
The film chronicles the rise and fall of popular contestant Charles Van Doren
after the fixed loss of Herb Stempel and Goodwin's subsequent probe.
The film stars John Turturro as Stempel, Rob Morrow as
Goodwin, and Ralph Fiennes as Charles Van Doren.
Paul Scofield, David Paymer, Hank Azaria, Martin Scorsese, Mira
Sorvino, and Christopher McDonald play supporting roles.
The real Goodwin and Stempel served as technical advisors to the production.
The film received generally positive reviews and was nominated for several awards, including a
Best Picture Oscar nomination (among three others) and several Golden Globe Awards.
It grossed $52.2 million against a $31 million budget.
The film explores themes of investigation, manipulation,
manipulation of the media, game show, idealism.
The tone is emotional.